[footsteps]
[YURU (YOUNG)]
Father, what is this?
A passageway that connects
the Left and Right to the keep.
This was always here?
[MINE] A long time ago,
when this village
was still a castle,
the lord had this
secret passageway made.
Only a select few people
knew of it.
Be sure not to tell
anyone else about it
and avoid using it unless
you have no other choice.
The Left and Right's bases
at the village exit
are directly above us.
[Yuru (young) gasps]
Listen to me, Yuru.
Know that no matter
what happens in the future,
the Left and Right
are watching over you.
[Right chuckles]
We've been watchin' you
this whole time, Yuru.
Henceforth, we will be
lending our power to you,
as your daemons.
The Left and the Right.
Is that you?
[♪ opening theme song playing]
DAEMONS OF THE SHADOW REALM
[Right grunts]
So, Left, can this
sniveling brat
truly be our Master?
Enough of your prattling, Right.
Our master seems ill at ease.
[DERA] My humblest greetings.
Honored to meet you.
You're Dera, the retainer.
We've long had our eyes
on you as well.
Now tell me.
We took down those birds
because they seemed a threat
to our master,
but what were they?
[DERA] They're vehicles
of the modern world below.
Look, we're short on time
right now.
There's some scary folks here,
at least two.
Help us get down the mountain
quickly and safely,
-and then I'll explain.
-[RIGHT] Watch it.
Only our master
gets to order us around.
And that title
does not belong to you.
-We heed Yuru alone.
-[DERA] Yeah, I know that!
But I can't get him up to speed
right now!
-[GABBY] Lame.
-[Yuru gasps]
[GABBY] They look like
a pair of toughies.
So whose daemons are you,
Old Dude's?
[YURU] What is that
tooth monster?
[DERA] Crap,
they're here already!
How are you unscathed
after a friggin' grenade?
Sorry, but these chompers
can take a hit.
And they're not "monsters."
Rude.
Let's see.
You look to be about 16.
Are you this Yuru kid?
I am, but I'm 17.
No, not in their world.
Only by traditional counting.
[YURU] How so?
Well then. Asa's brother
is alive after all.
Asa?
[Yuru grunts]
[ASA] I'm gonna kill
everybody else.
-[Gabriel growls]
-Make this easy
and come with me.
[Yuru grunts]
The village massacre,
that was you?
You caught me.
Master Yuru,
just give us the order,
and you have our full strength
at your command.
[YURU] Order you? No way.
[RIGHT] Huh?
[YURU] You're the village's
sacred guardians.
I wouldn't dare
overstep my place.
[Gabby sighs]
[YURU] I won't make demands,
but I do have two requests.
First, please look for
any survivors in the village.
If you would, take them
somewhere safe.
Second, more personally,
I want to kill the runt myself.
Don't touch her.
[Gabby grunts]
Aside from that, it's up to you.
Do as you both please.
[Right laughs]
Do you hear that? Lucky us!
Seems like our new boss
is the hands-off type!
I can work with that!
EPISODE 2
"LEFT AND RIGHT"
[clattering]
[Yamaha grunting]
-[ASA] Old witch.
-[YAMAHA] Huh?
Don't think for a second
you're getting away
with what you've done.
One way or another,
I'm making you pay.
[Yamaha grunts]
[Danji gasps]
[Danji gasps, grunts]
[RIGHT] Do as we please?
Understood! [grunts]
[RIGHT] I'll get the villagers
somewhere safe.
Watch out, kid.
My other half is hot-blooded.
[Gabby gasps]
[LEFT] You heard my master.
I am to do as I please.
[Gabby yells]
He's loading another!
[Gabriel growls]
[Yuru gasps]
They show resilience, that lot.
-[YURU] I'll chase!
-Whoa! Ah, jeez.
Why bother?
Let's get off this mountain
already!
♪
[RIGHT] Oy... You alive?
-[Azami groans]
-[RIGHT] Oy!
[RIGHT] Oh! You are.
[AZAMI] Huh?
[RIGHT] Must be
someone else's blood.
You're unharmed.
That's good!
[footsteps]
[AZAMI] Huh?
[RIGHT] Oh, I always forget,
you silly mortals.
You can't see me.
[Azami gasps]
Not to worry, young'un!
I am no monster.
I'm here to take you
somewhere safe,
-without any bad guys!
-[thuds]
[RIGHT] Uh?
Uh-oh.
Insulting.
Everyone of these kids
fainted when they saw me.
That kinda hurts!
They butchered
every adult they found...
-[footsteps running]
-...but didn't lay a finger
on the children.
[ASA] Uh?
Oh, you see me, don't you?
[Asa grunts]
[RIGHT] Huh?
[Right yelling]
[Asa grunts]
Cheeky brat,
not even a fond greeting?
And that's one
dangerous power you got.
Normally, I'd be more than happy
to give you a fight,
but my master ordered...
[coughs] Uh?
[grunts] Come on!
Kids just don't have
the kind of respect
they had in my day! [scoffs]
[sniffs]
[RIGHT] That lass...
[Gabby grunts]
[Gabriel grunting]
[GABBY] You're kidding me.
I'm losing a two v one?
[Gabriel grunting]
[Left grunting]
[Gabby gasps]
[Left grunts]
[Gabby grunts]
Not again!
Asa!
Damn!
[Gabby grunts]
[ASA] I got you!
Thanks, you saved my bacon.
[YURU] Don't move!
You're going to tell me
who you are. Right now!
I am your little sister.
Like I had said.
[YURU] Don't lie to me!
You're way taller than Asa!
[ASA] The food's
much more nutritious
when you go down the mountain.
[YURU] You're also
too mean-looking to be Asa!
[ASA] Life's been tough.
I'm a bit jaded.
[Right shouts] Oy!
Family shouldn't draw arms
against each other!
She ain't lying.
I could smell the lass' blood,
and it was the same as yours.
You're siblings.
[YURU] Huh?
Then, if you're the real Asa,
who's the person who's been up
in the keep all these years?
-[ASA] An impostor.
-[Yuru gasps]
♪
[ASA] Ten years ago,
our parents grabbed me
and said we needed to run away
from the village in a hurry.
Afterward,
Granny and the others
feared you'd leave, as well.
To avoid that,
they created a new Asa,
designed to keep you
chained here.
You'd never leave
your little sister all alone,
so they exploited your kindness
as a diligent older brother.
The real Asa
is the one you see here,
the one in front of you.
[Yuru gasps]
[Yuru grunts softly,
breathes shakily]
You came here to have
that touching reunion,
didn't you?
Well, you got it,
so please back off, all right?
Dera, are you...
They're trying to get
their hands on you.
We know this
alleged Asa is strong,
but we don't know how strong.
If we drag this out here,
the village will pay the price.
[Yuru gasps]
[DERA] There are still survivors
to worry about.
[Yuru grunts softly]
[breathes shakily]
-[YURU] Listen...
-[BOTH] Hm?
You're gonna leave
the rest of the village alone.
In exchange,
I'll let the runt walk away.
All right?
-[ASA] It's a deal.
-Asa!
See you.
[whooshing]
[Gabby grunts]
Why aren't we capturing him?
[ASA] Because your wounds
need urgent attention.
At least we know he's safe,
so this mission was a success.
[Gabby grunts]
[ASA] Are you okay?
You know, your brother
is a decent shot.
-He really got me.
-Yeah.
-He's merciless, too.
[GABBY] Least he's alive.
[ASA] Yeah.
He's alive.
[Asa cries softly]
My big brother.
He's still alive.
♪
[Asa continues crying]
-[soft rumbling]
-[GABRIEL] Huh?
[Asa continues crying]
[GABBY] Barrier's back up.
We need to get out of here.
DAEMONS OF THE SHADOW REALM
[MAN] Those helicopters
sure were loud.
OLD HIGASHI VILLAGE TRAILHEAD
Wonder what was happening.
Maybe someone
was in danger up there.
From what I hear,
people go missing
on this mountain
from time to time.
There are even a handful
who've never been
heard from again.
[sighs]
It's like a horror story.
You know, the one that I mean.
What was it?
-Oh, the lost village!
-Yeah, that's it!
Hikers find themselves wandering
into an alternate world
without even realizing.
There's a village there,
even though maps say
there shouldn't be.
But when they try
to go back later,
the whole place has disappeared
without a trace.
[DERA] Hello, folks!
Hi.
Hey there, gentlemen.
-Were those mountain porters?
-Dressed up like that?
-[wind blows]
-[both scream]
[WOMAN] The wind's crazy!
[MAN] I think we're done here!
Good. We can't see
the village anymore.
The barrier must be up again.
[YURU] Does that mean
we can never go back?
[DERA]
Well, if you really want to,
it's not impossible.
But now, there are people
who know where the village is,
and how to get inside of it.
Considering that
you're their target,
I don't think a hiding place
like that will do you much good.
Best keep away, and blend in
with the world below.
Hang a right.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
Appreciate you waitin' for us!
Thanks, Hana!
Hey, what's goin' on, Dera?
All you said was you were
bringing a human back with you,
so why are there daemons too?
-[RIGHT] Oh!
-So, she's a seer.
Sorry!
[DERA] I know this is a lot,
but we've gotta run.
I'll get you caught up
as we make our escape.
Yuru's life is at risk here.
So, this kid's
one of the twins, huh?
And our friends here
are the Left and the Right.
Oy! What's this contraption?
It is a giant metal beast.
Well, they seem occupied.
Nice to meet you, Yuru.
Ah, likewise.
Just call me Hana.
Dera's junior. We work together
as daemon retainers.
Mind if I ask if those noses
are pickin' up
any other daemons nearby?
Seems like we're in the clear.
Then what do you say
we get somewhere crowded
before that stops
being the case?
-Get in, Yuru!
-Get in this thing?
I don't even know what it is,
much less what it does!
Fair enough.
This "thing" is called
an automobile.
So, it's used for traveling.
Uh, right! It's made
of metal and junk.
And this nice lady here
is the driver.
Uh, what else?
[engine starts]
Forget the rest of it,
there are horses in here,
and it goes real fast!
Makes sense.
[LEFT] Understood.
[YURU] Right.
[DERA] Seriously?
OLD HIGASHI VILLAGE TRAILHEAD
[GABBY] Stupid ride's
taking forever to get here.
You're sure we're not
still inside the barrier,
and they're lookin'
everywhere for us?
If that were true,
I wouldn't have any data.
WE'RE AT THE SIGN 2 KM FROM THE
OLD HIGASHI VILLAGE TRAILHEAD
[ASA] Not like it'd matter
if we were inside of it.
I'd just bust it open again.
[footsteps]
[JIN] Found them.
Thank you for waiting.
Sorry you had such a rough time.
Thanks, Jinny, nice to see you!
I appreciate you
coming all the way up
the mountain for us, Jin.
I heard some unexpected
daemons crashed your party.
Makes me wonder if I could've
turned the tides being there.
Prepare the stretcher
for Miss Gabby.
So, kiddo, how bad
are your wounds?
[GABBY]
They've stopped bleeding.
Still have an arrowhead
in my shoulder
I'll need removed later, though.
But we got the one
in my leg out clean.
[JIN] Those are both serious.
Don't talk about them
like some casual thing.
I'm fine, no biggie, man.
I'm used to dealing with pain.
Well, I'm concerned to see
that your brother
isn't with you.
He got away.
[JIN] So you did confirm
his existence?
He's alive and in good health.
[GABBY] Couldn't catch a glimpse
on your way up to us?
Didn't see any sign of him
as we came up,
even though we made sure
to secure all the trailheads.
They must have a shortcut
that we don't know about.
There's a possibility
they're still on the mountain.
-[MAN 3] If we had choppers.
-[Jin groans]
We lost two helicopters
and all of our soldiers.
The old man's gonna
have my head.
Gotcha covered, Jinny!
We can at least tell you
Asa's brother escaped
with some guy named Dera.
[JIN] Dera?
[GABBY] Probably the same guy
who killed all our soldiers.
Mr. Kagemori, could that be...
[grunts]
[JIN] It's the Tadera.
Of all days,
how'd we pick one
when a Tadera retainer
was here?
That proves it.
I should've brought
my pair along, after all.
[DERA] So to sum it up,
we released the Left and Right,
they took down some choppers,
then kicked some
enemy daemon butt.
I offed most
of the soldiers I found,
but there were so many,
I'm pretty sure a lot got away.
It takes a special kind
of pain in the ass
to send a bunch of soldiers
after one single kid.
You're tellin' me.
Figure it must've been
the Kagemori.
Are you for real?
[DERA] I guess they got my face
and name now.
I'll have to shave.
Probably move, too.
[HANA] Ah! All I wanted
was a peaceful life.
[LEFT] I sense daemons
approaching rapidly.
Seriously?
[DERA]
Great, we're being tailed?
[HANA] Come on, we just left!
[Left scoffs]
[LEFT] Fret not,
these two mean us no harm.
We know them well.
♪
[OSHIRASAMA] I'm pleased
to see you, my friends.
Since you've manifested here,
does that mean you've
found yourselves a new master?
Aye.
After being up there so long,
everything here seems foreign!
It has been nearly 400 years.
[RIGHT] Our new master
is the boy inside there.
[OSHIRASAMA]
Oh, that's wonderful!
I love children.
It just so happens,
he's one of the twins
who sunders night and day.
You've quite the challenge.
[horse neighs]
What do you plan to do now?
No clue.
They say we can hide inside
some busy human town
for the time being.
[OSHIRASAMA] Ah...
You must tell me all about it
when you return.
Fare thee well!
[horse neighs]
They were here?
They were here!
They really do exist!
A horse? So what?
Show some respect!
[HANA] That was Oshirasama!
[DERA] They're a legit god!
They're nothing like
your average daemon!
-Legit?
-[DERA] It means real!
I never thought I'd get
the chance to see them
while I'm still alive!
Ah! Life really
can be beautiful!
Do they not understand
we are the gods of the village
they just came from?
I detect a slight disparity
in treatment.
[YURU] So there's
a variety of demons?
[HANA] Sure are.
Us humans have a tendency
to sort them
into different genres.
[YURU] Genres?
[HANA] I should've said types,
or maybe categories?
We call some of them gods,
or spirits.
Some are like Oshirasama
and live a relaxed life
alongside humans.
Others bring good fortune,
but some are tricksters
that drive humans
to criminal activity.
[DERA] Those dentures
that attacked us
seemed all-in as a combat type.
It's a pair of upper
and lower jaws.
I've heard of daemons like that
eating their masters,
if they mistreat 'em.
I'm really sorry,
it's my fault.
I made the final call
to let him go.
If anyone has to be reprimanded,
then let it be me.
You can't go takin'
all the blame.
You only did it to protect me.
No need to sweat
the details, you two.
The old man
will be happy to know
he's alive and off the mountain.
So to that end,
the mission succeeded.
Still wanna make it clear
how toast I would've been
if Asa hadn't been there
to bail me out.
Are you saying his daemons
were that dangerous?
[GABBY] Well, they were
nothing to scoff at,
but it was the kid
who shot me with his bow.
First he shut down my mobility,
then my dominant hand.
[JIN] Oof. Scary brother
you got there.
[ASA] You should've seen him,
he's got the mind
of a die-hard hunter!
[thunder rumbling]
[rain pouring]
[men grunting]
[MAN 1] Damn it.
The rain's starting
to really come down.
If we don't meet up
with Mr. Kagemori soon,
they're probably gonna
leave us behind.
-Let's go...
-[both gasp]
[MAN 1] You're kidding me.
[grunts]
We've been to this spot
five times already.
We're screwed.
We can't leave.
[thunder rumbling]
[vehicles passing by]
♪
[♪ closing theme song playing]
NEXT EPISODE
PREVIEW
[YURU] Flush when you're done.
Make sure it goes down.
We're in Guntama.
[LEFT] Yes, Guntama.
[HANA] You got
another thing comin'
if you think I'd ever marry you!
EPISODE 3
"DERA AND HANA"